片名：神隐任务(2012/12/27上映)
Move!
不是无期就是死刑 詹姆斯
lt's life or death now, James.
要么死
By that,
l mean you're doing one or the other
要么在罗克维优监狱了此一生
up in Rockview.
这位是地方检查官 罗丁
This here is
District Attorney Rodin.
知道她对你的看法吗
Want to know what he's wondering?
你或像男人那样走出去
Whether you're gonna walk
like a man or cry like a pussy
或像女人哭啼地走进死囚牢房
on your way to the death house.
知道吗 检察官喜欢用针注射
See, the D.A. likes the needle,
然而我
whereas me,
我很想让你长命百岁
l like to see a man like you
live a long life
直到你所有牙都被打掉
with all your teeth knocked out.
被众人多的狱友同志暴菊
Passed around till a brother
can't tell your part from a yawn.
放屁都不响
Now, l don't know
what kind of man you are,
不知道你喜欢哪一种命运
which of these two fates you prefer,
罗丁是个仁慈的人
他会让你自己选择
but Rodin here is a generous fellow.
He's willing to let you take your pick.
如果你不想耗时费力
lf you save us and this city
a long and costly trial,
那就放弃聘请律师 马上承认罪行 立刻
waive your rightto counsel and confess,
right now.
16个小时了
Sixteen hours.
侦探 该有结果了
Has to be some kind of
record, Detective.
这是什么意思
What the hell is this?
杰克-雷彻是什么人
Who the hell is Jack Reacher?
杰克-雷彻 乳名杰克
Jack Reacher,
阿勒格尼县 地方检察官
没有中间名 像个幽灵
born Jack, not John, no middle name,
is a ghost.
没有中间名 像个幽灵
No driver's licence, current or expired.
No residence, current or former.
没有信用卡和用卡记录
没有手机 电子邮箱 什么都没有
No credit cards, no credit history.
No P.O. box, cell phone, e-mail.
没有
Nothing.
至少能告诉我他是谁吧
Can you at least tell me who he is?
可以告诉你他以前是谁
他家几代都是军人
Well, l can tell you who he was.
Blood military.
在国外的军事基地出生长大
Born and raised on bases abroad.
母亲是法国人 父亲在海军陆战队服役
Mother was a French national,
father in the Corps.
学校是是西点军校
His first trip to the United States
was to attend West Point.
四年以后 到海外执行任务
Four years later, he ships out for good.
伊拉克 阿富汗 巴尔干半岛 都去过
lraq. Afghanistan. The Balkans.
You name it.
出色地完成了各种任务
Served with distinction.
获得银星勋章 青铜星章 功勋勋章
Silver Star, Bronze Star,
Legion of Merit.
-国防部服役优秀勋章
-查查还有什么奖
Defence Superior Service Medal?
Had to look that one up.
还有紫心勋章 大部分服役时间都是在宪兵队度过的
据传他是个非常杰出的特工
And a Purple Heart.
He spent the bulk of his service
据传他是个非常杰出的特工
in the Military Police.
By all accounts, a brilliant investigator.
但显然也是个麻烦制造者
Apparently, a troublemaker, too.
被降职为上尉
Demoted to Captain.
后来又升到了上校
Worked his way back to Major.
两年前他申请退役
Then two years ago, he musters out.
在部队里度过了大部分时间
After a literal lifetime in the military,
he just up and quits. And then,
又突然退伍
for only the second time in his life,
然后第二次进入美国
之后就从人间蒸发了
he enters the United States
and simply disappears.
死了？
Dead, maybe?
不
Not according to Social Security
and a bank account in Virginia.
根据社保和弗吉尼亚银行帐户信息看
他的退休金按月存入
His pension is deposited monthly
有人通过银行转帐把钱取走(西联银行)
and someone is making the occasional
withdrawal. All wire transfers.
没有联邦搜查令 无法查出在哪取钱
l can't find out where
without a federal warrant.
他不开车 也不开飞机
Well, he can't drive or fly.
至少不是真名
At least not under his real name.
有拘捕令吗 有没有犯罪记录
-Any warrants?
-Record's clean.
算了吧 这么难找的人
一定能找到理由通缉他
Come on! A guy this hard to find?
Gotta be wanted for something.
他没有任何犯罪记录
His record is clean.
那么
So,
怎么才能找到这个雷彻
how do we find this Reacher?
你无法找到 除非他想让你找到他
Obviously, you don't find this guy
unless he wants to be found.
打扫一下长官
有个叫杰克-雷彻的人想见你
Excuse me, sir. There's
a Jack Reacher here to see you.
你有什么事吗
Can l help you?
詹姆斯-巴尔
James Barr.
好了 你见过他了 你们怎么认识的
So, now you've seen him.
How do you know him?
为什么不对他实行保护性监禁
Why wasn't he in protective custody?
是工作疏忽
That was an oversight.
是监狱里的势利小人把他扔进了狼窝
More like some Corrections flunky
threw him to the wolves.
好像是这样
Just as likely.
可是事到如今已经无法挽回
But it's done and we can't undo it.
现在怎么样了
So what happens now?
好吧 现在他处在昏迷中
Well, now he's in a coma.
他昏迷不醒
We'll try him when he wakes up.
lf he wakes up.
如果他能醒过来 我们要审判他
好了该你谈谈了 雷彻
Okay? Now it's your turn, Reacher.
他为什么要你做证人
Why did he call you as a witness?
我不相信他会这么做
l don't believe he did.
他指名道姓要你来
Well, l believe
he asked for you by name.
我能看一下证据吗
Any chance l could look
at the evidence?
你回答完几个问题再说
No way.
Not till you answer some questions.
很高兴认识你
Nice meeting you.
嗨 嗨 嗨!
站住 雷彻先生
-Hey. Hey. Hey!
-Mr Reacher.
- 嘿 别动
- 嗨，站在原地别动
-Mr Reacher!
-Hey, stop! Stop right there!
我们有有言在先
We had a deal.
我带你去见巴尔 你告诉我你了解的情况
l take you to Barr,
you tell me what you know.
你说他射杀了五个人 可是他昏迷不醒
l know you say he shot five people,
l know he's in a coma.
有个公交车站
l know there's a bus station
three miles away
我用24分钟走到那
and l can walk there in 24 minutes.
你要放弃你的朋友
So you're just going to
walk out on your friend?
- 他不是我的朋友
- 那他为什么会要求你来
-He's not my friend.
-Why'd he ask for you,then?
跟他杀死五个人是一个原因
Well, same reason he shot five people,
he's crazy.
他疯了 等一下
Hey. Hold on.
别拦着我
Don't do that.
你们俩这么做卑鄙了
Well, this is a new low,
even for both of you.
没有我在场 你们不能和我的委托人谈话
You do not talk to my client
without me present.
你知道
You know that.
我们没有和他谈话 他处在昏迷之中
We weren't talking to your client.
He's in a coma, for Christ's sakes.
- 你是巴尔的律师
- 海伦-罗丁 杰克-雷彻
-You're Barr's attorney?
-Helen Rodin, Jack Reacher.
- 杰克-雷彻?
- 海伦罗丁
-Jack Reacher?
-Helen Rodin.
是的 她是地方检察官的女儿
Yeah, she's the
District Attorney's daughter.
这事儿说来话长
lt's a good story, actually.
l'd like to hear it.
你们是怎么找到他的
How'd you find him?
How'd they find you?
你不能和这个人谈话
You can't be talking to this man.
Two strikes in one day.
不是你想像的那样 是他找到的我们
-lt's not what it looks like.
-He came to us.
- 你见了检察官
- 这样做违法吗
-You went to the D.A.?
-ls there a law against that?
目前你还没有违法
None you're currently breaking.
行啦 别把大家搞得下不来台
Come on, before this gets awkward.
Now, hey.
快说 法庭上见
Say, "See you in court." For me.
再见侦探
Goodbye, Detective.
- 很高兴认识你
- 我也是
-Weird meeting you.
-Likewise.
走吧
Let's go.
So...
你是杰克-雷彻
你是检察官的女儿
So, you're Jack Reacher.
走吧
-So you're the D.A.'s daughter.
-Oh, Jesus. Please.
－上帝 这种工作关系合法吗
－幸运的是合法
-ls that even legal?
-Fortunately.
－怎么会有这种安排
－你宣誓作证之后再告诉你
-How does that happen?
-l'll tell you after deposition.
别让我宣誓作证
You don't want to depose me.
你是被告证人
Oh, well, you're my only
defence witness.
- 我不是
- 你的朋友詹姆斯认为你是
-l'm not a defence witness.
-Your friend James thinks you are.
为什么所有人都认为他是我朋友
He's not my friend.
Why does everyone assume that?
为什么所有人都认为他是我的朋友
Well, why else would he ask for you
他要求见你 你来帮助他
and why would you
come here to help him?
我不是来帮助他 是为了把他埋了
l didn't come here to help him.
l came here to bury him.
(布鲁希尔建筑公司)
林斯基
Linsky.
杰克-雷彻是什么人
Who the hell is Jack Reacher?
-你为什么这么难找
- 不可能找到我的
-So why are you so hard to find?
-l'm impossible to find.
为什么找不到
Why is that?
这么说吧 这是我的职业习惯
Well, you could say it started out as an
exercise and became an addiction.
你逃跑吗
Are you on the run?
我的车要开了 快点吧 律师
My bus is leaving.
You better hurry, counsellor.
你是怎么认识巴尔的
How do you know James Barr?
-你为什么要替他辩护
-我是律师
-Why are you representing him?
-l'm a lawyer.
公共辩护人也有机会证明他无罪
So is a public defender, with just as
much chance of clearing Barr.
我并不是想证明他无罪
l'm not trying to clear him,
而是要他不被判死刑
l am just trying
to keep him off death row.
-你想证明他精神失常
-这也是一种选择
-By proving he's insane?
-Well, that's one option.
跟你爸爸做对
And sticking it to your father because...
不是他 是地方检察官办公室
No. Not my father.
The Office of the District Attorney.
因为地方检察官办公室从未承认你是淑女
Because the Office of the District
Attorney never bought you a pony.
罗丁检察官从未打输过死刑的案件
知道为什么吗
D.A. Rodin's never lost a capital case.
You know why?
政客都爱仗势欺人
lmpeccable tailoring.
-他从来都不接打不赢的案子
-知己知彼
-He never picks a fight he can'twin.
-Worked for the Red Baron.
每个谋杀嫌疑犯都有两个选择
Every murder suspect in this town
is given a choice.
认罪或者面对死刑
Confess or face death.
和从未输过的检察官打官司
Against a D.A. who never loses.
我的律师事务所相信无罪的人
My firm has reason to believe
more than one innocent man
但都会毫不抵抗就认罪伏法
has gone down without a fight.
我明白了
Oh, l get it.
你是个理想主义者
You're an idealist.
不 我是和平主义者
No. l'm a pacifist.
想废除死刑是高尚行为
lt's a noble crusade.
但这次你打不赢 相信我
詹姆斯-巴尔有罪
But this is not the fight. Trust me.
James Barr's guilty.
你还没看证据呢
You haven't even seen the evidence.
这是保密谈话吗
ls this a privileged conversation?
对 是对诉讼委托人的谈话
你说的每一句话都不能转述
Of course, it's a client conference.
Nothing you say here can be repeated.
有四种人会参军
There are four types of people
who join the military.
有人是为了家族荣誉
For some, it's a family trade.
有爱国者渴望为国效劳
Others are patriots, eager to serve.
还有些为了工作
Next, you have those
who just need a job.
最后一类是想要一种合法的杀人方式
Then there's the kind who want a legal
means of killing other people.
詹姆斯-巴尔就是这种人
James Barr was one of those.
他当上了狙击手
He made sniper.
刻苦训练 一周2000次
Trained hard.
Two thousand rounds a week.
每枪都要求射中脑门
And with every shot,
he's taught to visualise
就是要一击致命
the base of a man's skull
through his reticle.
出血少 死的快
The sweet spot where
the medulla meets the spine.
Visualise that puff of pink mist.
他终于被派往伊拉克
Finally, he's deployed to lraq.
安排他去掩护射击组
He's put on overwatch.
日复一日 他通过瞄准镜盯着平民
All day long
he stares through a scope at civilians.
女人
Women.
孩子
Children.
日复一日 漫长的2年
Day in, day out, for two long years
没接到命令发过一枪
without ever once being
cleared to fire a single shot.
后来开始撤军
Then comes the drawdown.
对詹姆斯-巴尔来说 战争结束了
For James Barr, the war's over.
一周射击2000次
Two thousand rounds a week.
他职业生涯总共射击25万次
竟然没有一枪是真人做靶子
A quarter million rounds in his career,
not one at a human target.
人处于饥饿之中 会饥不择食
You've been hungry.
You've been horny.
身上痒痒又挠不着
You've had an itch you can't scratch.
想像那种感觉
lmagine that feeling.
Days. Weeks. Years.
天天年年 这种难受要经历25万次
lmagine that feeling times 200,000,
plus 50,000 more.
设想一下 在54度的高温下站岗
明天就要回家了 知道吗
lmagine it's 130 degrees on the deck
and tomorrow you're going home
如果你现在不挠痒痒 就永远没机会了
and you know if you don't
scratch that itch now,
需要发泄一下
you never will.
需要一个目标
You need a release.
需要找一个目标
You need a target.
而他的大脑从未有过明确目标
And the who of it
never once enters your mind.
他隐蔽得非常好
He covered his tracks well,
跟神志清醒的人一样
just like sane people do.
可是我抓到了他 事实面前他认了罪
He almost got away with it, too.
But l caught him. And he confessed.
那他为什么没进监狱
So why didn't he go to prison?
巴尔不知道他杀的安保人员
What Barr didn't know that day was the
four civilian contractors he'd picked off
是参加过集体强奸晚会的人
just spent the weekend
at what they call a rape-rally.
28个女人 从11岁到54岁
lt was 28 women,
ages 54 on down to 11.
这些人是我在结案前找到的
Those were just the ones l could find
before the case was shut down.
挖得越深 越令人发指
See, the deeper l dug, the uglier it got.
七年 伟大的任务之后
And after seven long years
of"Mission Accomplished,"
安保公司的人想隐瞒真相
someone in the corporation just wanted
the whole thing to end quietly.
把此案归结为战争导致的人精神失常
让杀人犯一走了之
So they chalked it up to the fog of war,
made the murders go away.
这是绝密信息
This is classified information.
所以是保密谈话
And that's why the privilege.
但你可以把这些告诉检察官
But you were ready
to tell this to the D.A.
我上次见到巴尔时 向他做过承诺
The last time l saw Barr,
l made him a promise.
当我看到这个消息 就过来兑现承诺
And when l saw his name on the news,
l came here to keep it.
-现在知道不用这么做了
-你怎么会这么肯定
-But now l know l don't have to.
-How can you be sure?
你还没有看过证据
You still haven't seen the evidence.
你父亲看过了 他不会接打不赢的官司
Your father has.
And he doesn't pick a fight he can't win.
巴尔不会再逃脱杀人罪名
Barr's not getting away
with murder again.
有可能
He might.
在监狱里 他大脑受到严重损伤
He suffered a severe brain injury
in state custody.
如果他能醒来
When he wakes up, if he wakes up,
可能会不记得这件事 或者什么都不记得
he may not remember the event,
he may not remember anything at all.
这个案子不是巴尔有罪或无罪
And this case won't be about
James Barr's guilt or innocence.
而是他能否接受审判
lt'll be about his ability to stand trial.
我把一切都告诉了你 你还想为他辩护吗
After everything l just told you,
you still want to defend him?
我想看到他受到公正的审判
l want to see he gets a fair trial.
你说过他在巴格达已经认罪了
You said he confessed in Baghdad.
他这次没有承认
He didn't confess this time.
这次他做的孽更多 他要求见你
-This time he knows better.
-This time he asked for you.
我想要知道为什么
l want to know why.
你想要知道为什么
这次他做的孽更多 他要求见你
You want to know why.
l can see it's eating you.
你无法问巴尔
And you can't ask Barr,
检察官又不让你看证据
and the D.A. won't let you
see the evidence.
我的首席调查员可以看出那些证据
My lead investigator has complete
access to the evidence. All of it.
你的首席调查员在哪儿   他要出城了
-So where's your lead investigator?
-About to catch a bus out of town.
谢谢你的咖啡 律师
Thanks for the coffee, counsellor.
你要明白 你不仅让我看证据
You understand you're not just
asking me to look at the evidence.
还要让我看那个准备杀手
You're asking me to look
at a cold-blooded killer.
我知道她是个有罪的人
A man l know to be guilty.
A man you want to keep off death row.
即使你不想看到他被判死刑
And you're asking me
to look at him objectively.
你要求我客观地看待他
Yes, that is what l'm asking.
是的 这就是我的要求
l'll do it. On one condition.
我接了 但有一个条件 说吧
Name it.
你必须客观地看待受害者
You have to look
at the victims objectively.
你建议我怎么做
How do you suggest l do that?
谁 法里奥尔先生吗
-Yes?
-Mr Farrior?
我是海伦-罗丁 我们通过电话
l'm Helen Rodin.
We spoke on the phone.
当然
Of course.
你要为那人辩护
You said you're defending
the man that ki...
That man.
我要做詹姆斯-巴尔的辩护律师
l represent James Barr, yes.
你要问关于我女儿的问题吗
And you have questions
about my daughter?
是的
l do.
为什么
What for?
我希望了解受害者是什么人
l was hoping to get a better sense
of who the victims were as...
就是说 他们是什么样人
That is to say, who they were as people.
As human beings.
考虑到你的地位 这不正常 是不是
That's a bit unusual,
considering your position, isn't it?
说得对
That is true.
通常情况下 处在我这个地位的人
Normally someone in my position
would want the jury
应该让陪审团知道得越少越好
to know as little as possible about the...
你的当事人杀了那么多人
The people that your client killed.
冷酷无情
ln cold blood.
你和其它家庭的人谈过了吗
Have you spoken
with the other families?
是的, 有几个人愿意和我谈
Yeah, some.
The ones who would speak with me.
进来
Come in.
谢谢
Thank you.
Chrissie was a nanny.
克里希姆是个保姆 那天她领着个小孩
She had a little girl with her that day.
是的 我知道
Yes, l know.
你要和那个孩子谈话吗
Are you gonna go talk with that child?
不 当然不
No, of course not. l...
为什么不
Why not?
我觉得有点太残酷
-Well, l think it would be...
-lnsensitive?
不合适
lnappropriate?
你想要知道关于我女儿的材料
Everything that you want to know
about my daughter
都在这
is right here.
报上对她作了全面的报道
The Gazette did a nice piece on her.
她的讣告上做了其它说明
Her obituary does the rest.
谢谢 我一定好好看看
Thank you. l'll definitely have a look.
你是个好律师 罗丁小姐
You a good attorney, Miss Rodin?
我真的不应该
-That's not really for me to...
-Just
别打岔
answer the question.
直接回答问题
Yes, l suppose l am pretty good.
是的 我认为自己是个优秀律师
Good enough to keep
that man off death row?
你知道
You know,
优秀的足以能让巴尔免除死刑
l think maybe l should go.
也许我该走了    请等下
You stay where you are.
那个人死有余辜
That man deserves to die, Miss Rodin.
你为什么要为他辩护
Why would you defend him?
我犯了严重的错误
l can see
that l have made a terrible mistake.
非常抱歉 我保证再也不来打扰您
And l'm very, very sorry
and l promise l won't bother you again.
哈罗,爸爸
Hello, Dad.
你在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
我在干什么 怎么了
What am l... What?
是真的吗
ls it true?
你在和受害者的家人谈话 你一个人
You're talking to the victims' families
You? Alone?
你怎么知道的
How do you know that?
How did you find me here?
我是地方检察官居 了解情况是我的工作
l'm the District Attorney.
lt's my business to know.
这不是回答问题
That's not an answer.
好了 你不是能力超强的调查员
Well, you're not the only one
with crack investigators, Helen.
对了 我知道雷彻的情况
That's right. l know about Reacher.
你的首席调查员
Your lead investigator is a war veteran
是失踪两年的老兵
who's been missing
for the last two years.
你如何能担保他情绪稳定
How can you vouch
for his state of mind?
并相信他 告诉你的一切
How can you trust anything he tells you?
你根本不了解他
You don't know the man.
告诉我
Tell me this,
does he know you can't pay him?
他知道你不能付他报酬吗
That your own firm
didn't want this case?
你的律师不想接这个案子吗
That nobody wants this case?
没人愿意接这个案子 在你的委托人醒来之前
You never even spoke to your client
before he wound up in a coma.
你从未和他谈过话 听我说 听着
我是作为你的父亲和你说话
Oh, now listen to me! Listen.
Listen, l'm speaking as your father.
无论我们之间有何分岐
Whatever our differences
have been in the past,
你都应该听我的
you gotta listen to me now.
你正在犯一个可怕的错误
You're making a terrible mistake.
你不能够赢得这场官司
You cannot win this case.
会毁了你的事业
为了什么 为了什么
You're going to ruin your career.
Why? For what?
为了伤害我吗
To hurt me? To change me?
- 海伦
- 别碰我
-Helen...
-Don't touch me!
谢谢让我参观
Thanks for letting me take a look.
我们喜欢被告的朋友
Hey. We love it
when friends of the accused
把我们的工作贬得一无是处
try to tear our work to shreds.
他不是我的朋友
He's not my friend.
你接着说 发现什么漏洞了吗
So you keep saying. Find any holes?
你们没必要让他住进医院
Well, you didn't have to
put him in the hospital.
除此之外 警察的工作也干得很漂亮
Other than that, damn fine police work.
lt's open and shut.
结案并不难 我能说什么呢
犯罪现场是座金矿
What can l say?
The scene was a gold mine.
我们都知道只有高手才能挖到金子
Come on. Now we both know
gold's only as good as the man digging.
你想来随时都可以
Yeah, well, anytime you want to come
back, take a look at this stuff...
不 谢谢 没这个必要
No, thanks. Don't need to.
你从来不记笔记
You never took any notes.
没必要
l don't need to.
你可真是军队里的大能人
So you were some real hot shit
in the Army, huh?
我干得还行吧
l did all right.
军队里都干些什么
So what does an Army cop do mostly?
Break up bar fights?
给酒吧斗殴的人拉架
不 我和你不一样
l did what you do pretty much,
with one minor difference.
只有一点区别 什么区别
What's that?
每个嫌疑犯都是训练有素的杀手
Every suspect was a trained killer.
再次谢谢
Thanks again.
你认为他为什么要付费停车
Why do you think he paid for parking?
Pardon?
他向陌生的人发射6颗子弹
He's about to fire six shots
into a crowd of strangers.
会担心女抄表员给他罚单
And he's worried about the meter maid?
精神病 解释不通吗
"Simple loony" won't do it for you?
我喜欢有另外一个推理
l like to have
at least one alternate theory.
习惯
Habit.
肌肉记忆
Muscle memory.
他不知道自己在做这种事
l don't think he knew he was doing it.
我说过了 干得真漂亮
Like l said, it's damn fine work.
大兵
Hey, Army.
步枪上面的序列号是多少
What's the serial number on the rifle?
硬币上面的年份是哪一年
What's the date on the quarter?
1968.
只见树木
Forest for the trees, Detective.
不见森林 侦探
Forest for the trees.
不介意一起坐吧
Mind if l share your table?
我是桑迪
l'm Sandy.
沙地 我上周去过沙地
So was l. Last week.
在海滩上 佛罗里达
On a beach, in Florida.
你的名字
What's your name?
吉米瑞斯
Jimmie Reese.
你看上去不像是吉米
You don't look like a Jimmie.
那像谁
What do l look like?
我不知道 但不像吉米
l don't know. But not a Jimmie.
你是新来的吧
So you're new in town?
算是吧
Usually.
这里太吵了
lt's kind of loud in here.
你也许想去静一点的地方 我有车
Do you want to maybe go
someplace quieter? l have a car.
你够开车的年龄吗
You're old enough to drive?
我到了能做很多事情的年龄
l'm old enough to do a lot of things.
我在节省开始 桑迪
l'm on a budget, Sandy.
什么
What?
我买不起你
l can't afford you.
我不是妓女
l'm not a hooker.
我真的没钱和你处朋友
Then l really can't afford you.
认真点 我在汽车零件商店工作
Seriously, l work at the auto parts store.
我是说 人们都愿意花最少钱玩儿女人
What l mean is, the cheapest woman
tends to be the one you pay for.
我不是妓女
l am not a hooker!
我不过开个玩笑
No. A hooker would get the joke.
-这是在干什么
-他说我是妓女
-What's this?
-He called me a whore.
那是真的吗
ls that true?
好吧 没人说她是妓女
而我说她是荡妇
Well, nobody said whore.
She inferred hooker, but l meant slut.
她是我们的妹妹
Hey. That's our sister.
她是接吻高手吗
ls she a good kisser?
出去
Hey. Outside.
先把帐结了
Pay your cheque first.
我一会儿再付
l'll pay later.
一会儿就付不了了
You won't be able to.
你认为会是这样吗
You think?
一直是 你试试看
All the time. You should try it.
我要狠揍你一顿
lt's a great joke,
but l'm going to beat your ass.
你想在这里打还是外面
Do you want to do that here or outside?
外面
Outside.
呆在这里 桑迪
Stay here, Sandy.
我不介意看见血
l don't mind the sight of blood.
看见出血 你才像个姑娘
When it means
you're not pregnant, anyway.
你还以为你是个牛仔 傻瓜
You still think you're funny now, creep?
闭嘴 桑迪 没人跟你说话
Shut your mouth, Sandy!
No one is talking to you.
你现在走还来得及
lt's your last chance to walk away.
你在开玩笑吗 五对一
Are you kidding? lt's five against one.
三对一 你不识数吗
lt's three against one.
我只要先打倒你
How do you figure?
就能轻易解决那两个跟屁虫
Well, once l take out the leader,
which is you,
最后两个人
l'll have to contend
with one or two enthusiastic wingmen.
就会逃之夭夭
The last two guys, they always run.
你以前干过这种事
You've done this before?
是的
Yeah.
天不早了
lt's getting late.
记住
Remember,
这是你自找的
you wanted this.
好了 你完蛋了
lt's okay. You're okay.
起来
Get up.
好
Okay.
现在知道谁是跟屁虫了
Now we know who's who.
我们把架打完吧
Let's get this done.
还想打吗
Really?
该死
Shit!
趴在地上
On the ground!
伙计们反应也太神速了
That's a pretty impressive
response time, fellas.
趴下
Do it!
手放在背后
Hands behind your back.
谁雇的你
Who hired you?
走
Let's go.
嗨 海伦
Hey, Helen.
我是不是喷了太多的香水
Am l wearing too much perfume?
我有鼻炎 爱默生侦探
Breathing too sternly.
Detective Emerson.
- 有人死了吗?
- 如果死了呢
-Somebody dead?
-And if someone is?
那他们也是羞辱死的 我下手很轻
Then they died of shame.
'Cause l was being gentle.
我现在明白你为什么到处走 雷彻
l'm starting to understand
why you move around a lot, Reacher.
有人死了么
So no one's dead.
有个小子可能再也走不了路了
One guy
likely won't ever walk right again.
-你想起诉我吗
-很想
-You want to charge me.
-Very much.
可是没有人要告我
But no one's pressing.
很遗憾 没有
Sadly, no.
我可以自由了吗
Am l free to go?
爱默生
Hey, Emerson.
4862681.
那是什么
What's that?
巴尔步枪上面的序列号
lt's the serial number on Barr's rifle.
你在为我工作 知道吗
You're working for me,
do you understand that?
你做的每件事都给我的律师所
So everything you do
is a reflection on my firm. On me.
造成恶劣的影响
l was set up.
-我被人陷害了
-你在和律师说话
You're talking to a lawyer.
有个女孩 她主动找我 故意找茬
There was this girl. She came onto me.
Picked a fight.
这事总在酒吧发生
Which never happens in a bar.
当我告诉她我叫什么名字时
She was thrown
when l told her my name.
她很吃惊 她遇到了拳王泰森
She was expecting Mike Tyson?
她不相信我是吉米瑞斯
She wasn't expecting Jimmie Reese.
扬基队的二垒手
Yankees second baseman.
为什么你要说是二垒手
Why did you say you were
a Yankees second baseman?
我一直使用扬基队二垒手的名字
l always use Yankees second basemen.
又没说我就是扬基队的二垒手
l didn't say l was a Yankees
second baseman, l just said...
现在重点是
Look, the point is,
是她想听到杰克-雷彻这个名字
she was expecting to hear
"Jack Reacher."
她知道我是谁
She knew who l was.
还没打 警察就来了
And the cops were rolling
before the fight even started.
这五个小子是她的哥哥 算了吧
And those five guys are her brothers?
Come on.
有人派这几个小子来干掉我
Someone sent those boys
to put me down.
谁
Who?
如果今天有人跟踪你
lf someone followed you
at the river today,
可能是警察
it was probably a cop.
And l highly doubt...
有三件事警察从来不做
There are three things cops never do.
投民主党的票 开凯迪拉克
They don't vote Democrat,
they don't drive Cadillacs,
或者用私人汽车办案
and they never use personal vehicles.
不是警察
lt's not a cop.
私人侦探或检察官办公室的人
A P.l., then, or the D.A.'s office.
你认为你父亲会陷害我
You think your father's office
would set me up?
为什么有人要害你
Why would anyone set you up?
你有新线索
How was your day?
雷彻
lt went exactly the way l think
你预计的事发生了
you hoped it would.
是吗
You okay?
嗯
你有证据吗
What'd you learn?
克里希-法里奥尔 22岁
Chrissie Farrior was 22.
是保姆 照顾家人和朋友6岁的女儿
A nanny caring for the six-year-old
daughter of family friends.
她攒够了钱 要去中国旅游
She'd finally saved enough
money for a trip to China,
应该一周前启程
in fact, she should have left
the week before.
可是她看的小女孩要留下来和她过七岁生日
But the girl she cared for wanted
Chrissie to stay for her 7th birthday.
她们去城里买生日晚会穿的衣服
They'd gone downtown that day
to shop for a party dress.
瑞塔-科罗娜多
Rita Coronado worked as a cleaning
lady atthe River Cross Plaza.
是十字河购物中心的清洁工人
她上班经常迟到
She was usually late for work,
but she had a good reason.
因为她儿子马可9岁
Since her son Marco
was nine years old
她每天送儿子去学校
she had to personally drop him at
school to make sure he actually went.
她的付出得到了回报
But her dedication had paid off.
马可现在是名优秀学生
Marco was now an honour student.
为了奖励儿子刻苦学习
As a reward for all his hard work,
瑞塔第一次带他去看棒球比赛
Rita wastaking him
to his first baseball game.
事发当天下午 她在买票的路上
And she was on her way to pick up
the tickets that very afternoon.
南希霍尔特对她丈夫说的话是谎话
Nancy Holt's last words to her husband
were a lie.
- 我爱你孩子 再见
- 再见
-l love you, babe. See you!
-Bye.
她说要去保养汽车
She told him she was
taking her car to be serviced,
却开去了市中心
but in fact, she was headed downtown.
完美
lt's perfect.
她告诉服务员 不想在信用卡上
留下买过东西的记录
She told the clerk she didn't want the
purchase showing up on her credit card.
她想在结婚十周年纪念日
送给丈夫一个惊喜
She wanted to surprise her
husband for their 10th anniversary
-just a few days away.
-Thank you.
奥赖恩-阿彻一直都不喜欢
Oline Archer never liked
her husband's construction business,
她丈夫的建筑生意
even after helping him become one of
the largest contractors in the county.
由于疾病缠身 加上昂贵的诉讼费用
So it came as a relief when
his failing health and a costly lawsuit
他们被迫把公司卖给了竞争对手
were forcing them
to sell to the competition.
救命
Rob?
救命 救命
Help! Help!
她丈夫把一生都献给了公司
Her husband
had given his life for the company.
现在公司属于她了
But now that it was hers,
她却不愿卖掉
she couldn't bring herself to let it go.
那天 她为了保住她的生意
She was on her way
to secure a loan that day
去办理了抵押贷款
so she could keep the business
she'd always hated.
达伦-索耶和瑞塔在同一楼里上班
Darren Sawyer was
an investment broker
是名投资经纪人
in the same building where Rita worked.
她妻子说他回家越来越晚
His wife said
he'd grown increasingly distant of late.
她不记得和丈夫上一次说话是什么时候
但说的话都很难听
She can't remember their last words
to one another, but they weren't kind.
达伦的尸体旁有束玫瑰花
Darren's body was found beside
a fresh bouquet of roses
是他那天早晨买的
he'd bought that morning
让他妻子感到欣慰的是
and his wife takes comfort
in the fact that, in his last moments,
丈夫在弥留之际还在思念她
he was most likely thinking of her.
我们会没事
We're gonna be okay.
We're gonna be okay,
we're gonna be okay,
我们会没事
we're gonna be okay.
你搜集到了什么证据
So what'd you learn?
你是对的
You want me to say you were right.
不应该打这个官司
You want me to say
that this isn't the fight.
詹姆斯-巴尔该死
James Barr should die.
他死有余辜
Maybe he should.
我是说 有关遇害者的消息
l meant, what did you
learn about the victims.
你想听什么
What more do you want?
他们五个是无辜的
They were five innocent people
senselessly murdered.
莫名其妙地就被杀了
对不起 你穿上衬衫好吗
l'm sorry.
Could you please put a shit on?
这就我的衬衫
This is my shit.
你失行李箱丢失了
You lose your luggage?
我没行李
l don't have any luggage.
我刚才说了什么
What was l saying?
- 五个无辜的人
- 随意地被谋杀了 是的
-Five innocent people.
-Murdered at random, yes.
你知道在美国 每年有多少人死亡吗
You know how many people
die in this country every year?
250万人
Two and a half million.
每天
That means every day,
约有七千美国人闭上眼睛
roughly 7,000 average Americans
wake up for the last time.
上星期五 他们中的五个死在一起了
Last Friday, five of them converged
on a single spot and died together.
这是巧合吗
ls that random?
那你说是什么
What else would you call it?
可能达伦和南希之间有婚外情
Well, take Darren and Nanry.
Odds are they were having an affair.
你说什么
Excuse me?
人们不会在上班路上给妻子买花
You don't buy roses
for your wife on the way to work.
而是在回家的路上买
You buy them on the way home.
正常人不会担心信用卡上的付款记录
And you don't worry about a charge
showing up on your credit card
结婚纪念日在周末
when your anniversary is that weekend.
除非是想隐藏这个礼物
Unless it's the gift you're hiding.
她一直向前走
And that's why she kept walking
而其他人都在逃跑
while everyone else ran.
你无法证明你的推论
You can't prove that.
这很难吗
手机 电子邮件
How hard would it be?
Cell phones, e-mails.
只要有人愿意调查就行
All it takes is someone willing to dig.
你想说什么
What's your point exactly?
那两个遇害人不是偶然相遇
My point is that two of the victims
weren't there strictly by chance.
我需要一份巴尔合伙人的名单
l need a list of Barr's known associates.
他没有合伙人 很孤僻
There isn't one. He didn't have any.
他甚至都不和邻居说话
He's a classic loner.
He didn't even talk to his neighbours.
他是一个安静的人
从来不打扰别人
He was a quiet man.
Never bothered anyone.
是的
Yeah, exactly.
- 你有他的信用卡记录吗
- 我能拿到 要它做什么
-You have his credit card statement?
-l can get it. Why?
我需要他曾去过地方的清单
所有的地方
l need the list
of all the places he hung out.
酒吧 球场 俱乐部
Bars, bowling alleys, strip clubs,
射击场
gun ranges.
能记录到他去过的地方
Anywhere someone
would remember him.
你希望找到什么
What do we hope to find?
我需要睡一会儿
l need some sleep.
你也是
You, too.
你不是想要
You don't really think l'm gonna...
七点钟回来接我
Be back to pick me up at 7:00.
好的
Yep. Absolutely.
你和谁在一起
Who's with you?
发生什么事了
What happened?
哦是他 对不对
That's him, isn't it?
我看不见你
l ain't seeing you, man!
放松 发生什么事
Relax. What happened?
巴尔的律师雇了一名调查员
Barr's attorney hired an investigator.
叫雷彻  军队里的顶级高手
Name of Reacher.
Some sort of top-shelf Army cop.
他和巴尔同时在巴格达服役
He was in Baghdad
the same time as Barr.
怎么了
So?
巴尔点名要这个大兵
So Barr asked for this soldier by name.
他今天出现在高速公路桥
Then he shows up at the river today.
Then up on the highway.
他好像知道我们的事
Almost like he knew something.
你说过不喜欢别人向我们提问题
And you said we don't like
people asking questions.
对不喜欢
No, we sure don't.
所以我采取了措施
So l took steps.
你采取了措施
You took steps.
当地人 我哥们
Local people. My guys.
你要遭报应了
And it blew back on you.
我以为他们五个人能解决问题
l figured five guys would do it.
你已经超越了你的权限 到此为止
This franchise was yours to manage.
下一步是我们的事 明白吗
That's all. Maintenance is our thing,
you understand?
我知道 我无法联系你
Yeah, l understand. l couldn't reach you!
这是我们的工作方式
Well, that's how this works.
好吧 我必须作决定
Well, l had to make a decision!
- 这些本地人  我需要他们的名字
- 在文件中
-These locals, l wanttheir names.
-lt's in the file.
他们中有人认识你吗
Any ofthem knowwho you are?
有一个 但我已经解决了
Just one, but l took care of it.
你
You...
-尸体在哪
-已经分尸了
-Where's the body?
-lt's distributed.
放松 没有人去找它
Relax! No one's gonna find it.
- 假如我们要找呢
- 为什么
-Suppose we want it found, yeah?
-Why the hell would you want it found?
我们有自己的方式
'Cause we got a way of doing things
so they stay done.
干净利落
Clean!
丢了一个人就干净了
A missing person isn't clean.
你本想杀一人却殃及了五个人
Christ's sakes, man. You only had to kill
one goddamn person.
这就是你说的干净 我说的是不露马脚
You tapped five! You call that clean?
他们找的是射手 不是靶子
l call it done. They're looking
at the shooter, not the target.
上帝
Jesus.
现在事情一团糟 以后不能再乱了
We make it messy now
so it won't get messy later.
我们不能留下任何问题
And we don't leave
questions unanswered ever.
永久不留 好吧 我搞定
Okay, all right. Okay. l can fix this.
-睁开你的眼睛
- 不 我没看你
-Open your eyes.
-No, l ain't seeing you!
现在无所谓了
lt makes no difference now.
我犯错了
l made a mistake.
我还有用 告诉我怎么做
l mean, you can still use me,
just tell me how to fix...
要活命就别说搞不定 因为你搞不定
To survive.
Don't say "fix it," because you can't.
我们刚清理完一个乱摊子
你又弄出来一个
We covered up the one mess.
You made another.
好 你说得对
All right. You're right.
真的没错 对不起
You're right.
You're absolutely right. l'm sorry.
告诉我怎么做
Just tell me what l have to do.
我在西伯利亚的监狱中呆过
l was in prison in Siberia.
我穿着死人的衣服 度过了严冬
l spent my first winter
wearing a dead man's coat.
口袋破了
A hole in one pocket.
为了不让冻伤变成坏疽
l chewed these fingers off
我就吃掉了这几个指头
before the frostbite
could turn to gangrene.
这几个是为了逃避到硫矿劳动吃掉的
These l gave up
to avoid working in the sulphur mine.
就这样 我活了下来
而许多人死了
That is how l survived
when so many others did not.
像我这样的人 总会有用武之地
A man this rare can always be of use.
做给我看 让我看看你有多坚强
So show me. Show me you are rare.
让我看看为了生存 你会做任何事
Show me you'll do anything to survive.
我不明白
l don't understand.
吃掉你左手的手指
The fingers from your left hand.
你有刀吗
Have you... Have you got a knife?
我在西伯利亚里没有刀
Did l have a knife in Siberia?
算了吧 你在和我开玩笑
No... Come on, you've got to be kidding.
你办得到
You can do it.
做给我看
Show me.
天呐
Christ!
不能 我不能
Can't! l can't.
我真不明白
Always the bullet.
还得用子弹
-l can't!
-l don't understand.
我们怎么处理那个大兵
What do we do about the soldier?
老办法
What we always do.
巴尔的信用卡对帐单
目击证人证词 咖啡
Barr's credit card statement.
Eyewitness testimonies.
没加牛奶吧
Coffee. You take it black, right?
我能说什么 我在家里工作
Yeah. What can l say?
l take my work home.
巴尔的信用卡对帐单是个死胡同
Afraid Barr's credit card
statement's a dead end.
没有酒吧, 没有脱衣舞俱乐部
只有汽油和杂货店的帐单
No bars, no strip joints, nothing.
Pretty much just gas and groceries.
从这开始找  50到100英里内的射击场
l need you to look for gun ranges
between 100 and 150 miles from here.
只找300码以上射击距离的射击场
Limit your search to ranges
longer than 300 yards.
可以 你能告诉我为什么
Sure, if you tell me why.
巴尔一直都在星期六给汽车加满油
Barr consistently filled
his tank on Saturday,
星期天再加满一次
and again on Sunday.
说明周末是长途旅行
He took a long drive
almost every weekend.
- 他可能去任何地方
- 是的
-He could be going anywhere.
-Yes.
而且如果是酒吧 球场或脱衣舞俱乐部俱乐部
我们永远不会找它
And if it's bars, bowling alleys
or strip clubs, we'll never find it.
比赛用的射击场呢
But a Match-level gun range?
There might be two.
原因有两个 他自己做子弹
或者练习射击
And he made his own bullets.
That means he shot a lot.
我猜测每个星期六都要来
l'm guessing every Saturday.
也许和一位朋友来
Maybe with a friend.
为什么和他的朋友谈话那么重要
Why is it so important
you talk to his friends?
如果他有朋友
Assuming he had any.
在汽车配件商店停一下
Drop me at the auto parts store.
等等 哪家
l... Wait. Which one?
她说的那家汽车配件商店
l don't know.
She just said "the auto parts store."
她 谁
She? Who?
你能说具体点吗
Reacher, can you be
a little more specific?
我没说任何汽车配件商店
l didn't say "an auto parts store."
你记忆中哪家配件商店最有名
Which one stands out in your mind
as the auto parts store?
需要我等你吗
You want me to wait?
不用 我一会去办公室找你 你怎么去
-No, l'll meet you back atthe office later.
-How will you get there?
我搭车去
l'll hitch a ride.
你要买什么
Can l help you?
桑迪在这里上班吗
Sandy work here?
你有什么事
What's this about?
我有话和她说 是私事
So she does, thanks.
l need to speak with her.
她在工作
lt's a personal matter.
合法工作
-She's on the clock.
-Legal personal matter.
长官 你要干什么
What are you, a cop?
叫她出来
Call her out, Gary.
加里 有证件吗 叫桑迪
-l'm gonna need to see some l.D.
-Go get Sandy.
好吧 我要看你的证件
Well, l need to see something.
你想躺救护车里吗
How about the inside of an ambulance?
好 我报警
Okay, l'm calling the police.
我想桑迪不想让警察参与此事
l don't think Sandy wants
the police involved...
-Hello?
-...but let's ask.
嗨  你
Hey! You...
哈罗  我需要一些帮忙
Hello? l need some help.
Hello? Hey! You!
你 后面不允许去
No. You are not allowed
back in here, man!
该死
Shit.
你认识这个人吗
You know this guy?
告诉他
Tell him.
你先出去 加里
Give us a few, Gary.
听着 我不是  我不知道
Listen, l wasn't... l didn't know.
我不知道会发生那样的事
l didn't know that was going to happen!
都怪杰布
lt was Jeb.
那个大个子
The big guy.
杰布-奥利沃
Jeb Oliver.
他告诉我你是个猛男
我以为你能上勾
He told me you were a predator.
You were supposed to start groping me.
别伤害我
Just don't hurt me.
桑迪 坐下
Sandy, sit down.
我到哪能找到杰布
Where can l find Jeb?
我不知道 他今天没来上班
l don't know.
He didn't come to work today.
他在这儿上班
So he works here.
是的
Yeah.
他贩卖冰毒 是个疯子
lt's bullshit, though. He cooks crystal.
把他地址写下来
His address, write it down.
真的很抱歉 先生
l'm really sorry, mister.
你是个坐怀不乱的人
You were supposed to be a pervert.
我差点赚到100元
And it was an easy 100 bucks.
就那么点儿吗
That's all?
杰布让我做 我就得按他说的做
When Jeb asks, you do what he says.
我有麻烦吗
Am l in trouble?
把你的车借给我就没麻烦
Not if you lend me your car.
- 我没有车
- 你当然有 就在外面
-l don't have a car.
-Well, sure you do. lt's outside.
我猜那辆卡玛洛是你的
l'm guessing you're the Camaro.
把那辆小皮卡借给我
That whimsy little pickup
has Gary written all over it. Keys?
我不能 那是杰布的车
l can't. lt's Jeb's car!
我把车开到他家去
他是不会感到惊讶的
Well, won't he be surprised
when l drive it home for him.
你是什么人 先生
Who are you, mister?
真的吗
Really?
我只是一个不愿意被打扰的人
l'm just a guy
who wants to be left alone.
我六点下班
l get off work at six!
也许我们可以
Maybe we could...
桑迪 听着
Sandy, listen.
你是个可爱女孩
Now, you seem like a sweet girl.
你很漂亮
You're pretty.
聪明
You're obviously sharp,
给加里管帐
doing Gary's books for him.
你不能让这些家伙利用你
You don't have to
let these guys use you.
我这样的女孩只能干这个
lt's just what girls like me do.
你有钱吗
You got money?
有一点
A little.
你要出城几天
Get out of town for a couple of days.
为什么
Why?
去外地 桑迪
Get out of town, Sandy.
杰布在家吗
ls Jeb home?
我有房屋搜查令
l have a warrant to search the premises.
知道了
l see.
好吧 如果你不介意
Well, if you don't mind...
Get him! Get him! Get him!
我有这个
l got this!
好吧
Okay, okay.
好
All right.
不许动
Don't move.
我告诉你
l'll tell you what.
我要是动 你就开枪
When l move, you pull the trigger.
- 杰布在哪
- 他不在这里
-Where's Jeb?
-He's not here.
我在哪能找到他
Where can l find him?
我的手
Jesus! My hand!
你不该玩枪
我在哪能找到他
Well, you shouldn't play with guns.
Where can l find him?
你开他的车 应该你告诉我才对
You're the one driving his car. You tell...
我上次见到他 是出狱那天
The last l saw him,
we was all leaving jail.
他说他必须见一个人
He said he had to see a guy.
- 什么人 谁
- 我不知道
-What guy? Who?
-l don't know.
我不知道 我发誓
l don't know, l swear.
他妈妈吸多了
Next l know,
his mom woke up from a bender
他醒来后所有的东西就都丢了
and his shit's all gone.
他是那种不辞而别的人吗
ls he the sort to light out like that?
不是 他从来不丢下他妈妈不管
No, no, man.
He'd never leave his moms alone.
这事有点不对劲
Shit ain't right.
- 你有车吗
- 在外面
-Got a car?
-lt's outside.
钥匙
Keys.
我的手
在我口袋里
My hand, man. They're in my pock...
好 好
Okay, okay.
看看你的朋友
Now look at your friends.
现在看我的脸
Now look at my face.
还想见我吗
Do you ever want to see me again?
决不
No way.
我在偷你的汽车吗
Am l stealing your car?
你想用多久都行
Use it as long as you like.
你真讲究
You're very kind.
啊
我认为杰布已经死了
l think Jeb Oliver's dead.
- 谁是杰布
- 酒吧里那家伙
-Who's Jeb Oliver?
-He was the guy from the bar.
天啊 你把他打成什么样了
Jesus, how hard did you hit him?
不是我
What? No, not me.
是他杀
No, he was murdered.
凶手想造成他离开城里的假象
And someone tried to make it
look like he left town.
也许他真是走了
Well, maybe he just left town.
旅行还把浴帘装到行李中吗
You pack your shower curtain
when you travel?
这是你的结论吗
ls this what you base
your conclusions on?
你头怎么了
What is that on your head?
你不会想知道的
You don't want to know.
你想提交你的调查结果
You said on the phone
you wanted to submit your findings.
詹姆斯-巴尔 是个狙击手
不是最好, 也不是最差的
James Barr was a sniper.
Not the best, not the worst.
但是受过两年训练
But he trained non-stop for two years.
这种训练能起什么作用
What does training like that do?
任何训练都有作用
What does any training do?
技术变成反射 肌肉记忆
你不用思考
Skills become reflex. Muscle memory.
You do without thinking.
把战术灌给他们
lt also makes people who aren't
necessarily smart seem smart
使不聪明的人看上去很聪明
by beating some
tactical awareness into them.
99%的证据指控巴尔
Now, 99% of the evidence
your father has against Barr
在巴格达都没有发现
didn't exist in Baghdad,
不是因为巴尔聪明
而是因为他受过训练
not because Barr was smart,
but because he was trained.
在那个停车场开枪
射手的眼睛会受到阳光照射
See, from that garage,
the shooter had the sun in his eyes.
目标左右移动
对任何射手来说 都很难击中
Targets were moving left and right.
lt's difficult conditions for any sniper.
但是在巴格达 巴尔在停车场里
But Baghdad, you said Barr
was in a parking garage then.
因为在巴格达 太阳照在他背后
Because in Baghdad,
the sun's behind him.
目标是从正前方过来 列成一队
Targets coming straight ahead,
single file.
对普通射手来说 这是最理想的条件
ldeal conditions
for even an average shooter
同样的条件
and the exact same conditions
他在高速公路桥上也能找到
he would've had
up on that highway bridge.
在桥上 他甚至都不用下车
Up there, he would never even
have to get out of the van.
没有停车计时器
No parking meter.
没有摄像头
No camera.
不会留下任何作案痕迹
No trace evidence left behind.
And his escape is assured.
能轻松地逃走
Now, l'm not saying
that he couldn't have killed
他不可能在河边杀死那些人
those people at the river,
but he wouldn't have.
他不会用这种方式干
Not that way.
-那么 你是说他疯了
-不是
-So you're saying he's crazy.
-No.
那你是什么意思
Well, what exactly are you saying?
我相信任何证据
Any single piece of evidence l'd buy.
But all of it?
纤维 指纹 飞走的弹壳 连起来呢
Fibres, fingerprints, stray brass,
l mean...
究竟是谁付的停车费
And who the hell pays for parking?
神志是否正常
Sane or crazy,
that just doesn't make sense.
这都解释不通 巴尔想让人抓住她
Okay. So Barr, he wanted to get caught
and he wanted you to catch him.
-他想让你去抓他
-这也解释不了
That would not explain how Barr,
巴尔怎么会在那种情况下开枪
an average shooter firing
in poor conditions, never missed.
而且还没有失手
He did miss.
他失手了
He did.
崭新的子弹
A pristine bullet,
留在被击中的液体中
conveniently trapped
by a liquid backstop.
同样的子弹从巴尔的枪射击遇害者
The same bullet that tied
Barr's gun to the killings.
作为起诉书中重要证据是有争议的
And arguably the prosecution's single
most important piece of evidence.
如果巴尔想被抓住 他为何没有失手
lf Barr wanted to get caught,
he didn't miss.
这解释不通
Either way, it doesn't make sense.
如果他想逃 早就逃了
lf he wanted to get away with it,
he likely would have
如果他想被人抓住
and if he wanted to get caught,
巴尔不可能做到这么完美
Barr was incapable of such perfection.
-或者说他运气很好 6枪6中
Or maybe he just got lucky,
six shots out of six.
直到这些家伙抓住我之前
That's what l was willing to accept,
我愿意接受这个观点
then those guys took a run at me.
他们用错了人
Whoever sent them made a mistake.
那只是酒吧斗殴而已
lt was just a bar fight.
也许
Maybe.
或者是有人害怕了 想把我吓走
Or maybe someone got nervous,
tried to run me off.
或者把我打昏
Or put me in a coma,
right next to their patsy.
放在容易受骗的人身边
Patsy?
这么完美的犯罪现场
lt was such a great crime scene.
简直太完美了
No one stopped to think
it might be too great.
爱默生没想
Not Emerson.
你父亲也没想
Not your father.
甚至你也没想
Not even Barr's own defence attorney.
都认为巴尔有罪
But Barr knew l would,
巴尔知道我会怀疑
no matter how much
l wanted it to be true.
那就是他为什么要见我
That's why he asked for me.
等等
Wait.
你是说
Are you suggesting...
詹姆斯-巴尔 是无辜的
James Barr is innocent.
你知道这是什么想法吗
You can see what this is, can't you?
你接这个案子
You've got a case in your hands
也许是你最后一个
that may be
the last case you'll ever have
你却想方设法不结案
and you'll do anything
not to hit the bottom of it.
海伦
Helen.
海伦 你就不该退役
You know,
you never should have retired.
听着
Just, look. Listen.
据我所知 三天前
For all l know, you were
standing at an intersection
你还举牌子站在十字路口
with a cardboard sign three days ago.
而我竟然雇用了你
我的父亲是正确的
And l hired you.
Jesus, my father was right.
- 海伦 海伦
- 现在全明白了
-Helen. Helen.
-lt makes total sense now.
海伦 你那种生活方式 到处游荡
lt's the way you live,
the way you move around.
你不适应现实生活 是吗
You're just not cut out
for the real world, are you?
你害怕会有巴尔那样的下场
Are you afraid you'll end up like Barr?
-海伦
-这是什么
-Helen.
-ls that what this is?
看看窗外
Look out the window.
不我要工作要做你快走吧
No, l have work to do.
来吧
-And you need to leave.
-Just humour me. Okay.
放开我
Let go of me.
告诉我你见到了什么
-Would you tell me what you see?
-l see the same
我每天看过的东西
things l see every day.
好吧 设想一下你从没见过这些
Well, imagine you've never seen it.
想像你是在另一个地方度过人生
lmagine you've spent your whole life
in other parts of the world
你为自由而战
being told every day
you're defending freedom.
你终于无法忍受了
And finally
you decide you've had enough.
看看你为之奋斗的是什么
Time to see
what you've given up your whole life for.
为自己争取一些自由
Maybe get some of that freedom
for yourself.
看看这些人
Look at the people.
现在告诉我哪个是自由的
Now tell me which ones are free.
没债的
Free from debt.
焦虑
Anxiety.
压力
Stress.
恐惧
Fear.
失败 侮辱 背叛
Failure. lndignity. Betrayal.
人们都希望生来就知道现在的事
How many wish they were born
knowing what they know now?
问问自己 有多少人愿意
Ask yourself how many would do things
反覆做同一件事
the same way all over again?
有多少人愿意像我这样生活
And how many would
live their lives like me?
看看对面街上的那辆奥迪车
Now look at the silver Audi
across the street,
整天都在跟踪我
the one that's been following me all day.
那能证明什么
What does that prove?
这是车牌号 多久能查出车主
Here's the tag number.
How long would it take you to run it?
晚上 我不确定 一小时
At this time of night?
l don't know. An hour?
查吧
Do it.
查到后 我就离开
Do it, and then l'll leave.
什么时候
When?
不 这现在是我的问题 我来解决
No, this is my problem now.
l'll handle it.
是的
Yeah?
你暴露了
You're blown.
律师正在查车牌
The lawyer's running the licence plates.
是的
Yeah. So do it?
完成了
Done.
去这个住址
Go to this address.
好吧 假如巴尔没干这事
All right, let's just say
that Barr didn't do it.
或是有人指使他干的
Or did it 'cause someone
put him up to it.
你有什么证据
Either way, what have you got?
是阴谋
Conspiracy.
预谋杀死五个平民百姓 没有动机
Yeah, conspiracy to kill
five random people?
很荒唐 是吗
There's no motive.
荒唐的有点离谱
-lt's ridiculous, right?
-lt's grassy knoll ludicrous.
进一步调查没有意义了
No point looking any further.
没错
Exactly.
说得对
这是什么
What's this?
杀人动机
The motive. Just hold onto it.
我们在玩什么 猜迷游戏
What are we playing, Clue?
Yeah?
给我
Give it to me.
谢谢
Thank you.
你确信那辆汽车跟了你一天吗
You sure
that car was following you all day?
你接上 我就开始
As soon as you picked me up. Why?
这辆车属于乐班德尔公司
lt's registered to a company
called Lebendauer Enterprises.
预谋杀死五个平民
A conspiracy to kill five random people?
荒唐
That's ridiculous.
四个
Four.
四个平民
Four random people.
为了掩盖一个特定的目标
To hide one specific target.
有人想要奥赖恩-阿彻的建筑生意
Someone needed
Oline Archer's construction business.
而奥赖恩不愿意交出项目
And Oline wouldn't let it go.
这是一个合理的假设
lt's a convincing theory.
但是只是一个假设
But it's just a theory.
第一枪射击是最不准确的
The first round is the least accurate.
The snipers call it a cold shot.
狙击手称之为冷射
你的目击证人描述说
Meanwhile, your eyewitness
described a pause
第一枪和第二枪之间有停顿
between the first and second rounds.
第二枪射手很深稳
The one shot where the killer
took his time.
奥赖恩-阿彻是第二个遇害者
And Oline Archer
was the second victim.
这一枪 至关重要
The one shot that mattered.
这还只是猜测
But it's just a theory.
这是根据巴尔习惯而设的圈套
This frame was custom made for Barr.
选中他的人了解巴格达的事
Whoever chose him
knew about Baghdad
而能讲出这件事的人
and the only one who could have
told him about Baghdad
只有巴尔他自己
was Barr himself.
他至少会有一朋友 非常亲密的朋友
He has at least one friend.
A very close one.
找到他 才能找真正的凶手
Now, you find that friend,
you'll find the real shooter.
找到真正的凶手 雷彻
Find the real shooter? Reacher,
我的工作是向陪审团提出合理质疑
my job is to present the jury
with reasonable doubt. Period.
-要抓那些坏人 把他们绳之以法
-让他们接受法律制裁
What about catching the guys
who really did this?
-Catching the guys who did this?
-Bringing them to justice?
- 不 我不能拿这到法院
- 揭开事实真相
-No, l can't take this to court.
-Exposing the truth.
即使我相信巴尔是无辜的
Even if l believed Barr is innocent,
it's not my job.
那不是我的工作
我只是一个律师而不是警察
l am just a lawyer. l'm not a cop.
而且坦白说 你也不是
And frankly, neither are you.
我不能再这样做
l can't do this any more.
谢谢你的咖啡 大律师
Thanks for the coffee, counsellor.
桑迪
Sandy?
等等 是桑迪 不是吗
Wait, it is Sandy, isn't it?
我认识你吗
Do l know you?
查理 杰布的朋友?
Charlie. Jeb's friend?
太让我伤心了
Oh, come on, don't break my heart.
对不起 我不记得
l'm sorry, l don't remember.
我们当时都喝高了
Well, we were both pretty wasted.
哦 对
Yeah.
- 什么 你住在这儿
- 就在这楼上 真巧
-What, you live here?
-Just up there.
No shit.
我刚刚搬到那后面住
l just moved in around the back!
How crazy is that?
难以置信 有趣
lt's wild.
是啊
Yeah.
哇 你真漂亮
Wow! You look great.
谢谢
Thanks.
听着 我不想耽误你的时间
Well, look, you know,
l don't want to keep you, so...
也许我们可以找个时间喝一杯
Maybe we can grab a drink sometime.
是的  也许
Yeah, maybe.
今晚怎么样
Hey, how about tonight?
我约了人
l'm meeting some people.
好吧
Okay. Well, some other time, then.
那就改天吧
Some other time.
在这里动手
Do it here.
什么
What?
雷彻
Reacher!
俄亥俄州有个射击场
目标距离700码
There's a gun range in Ohio,
targets out to 700 yards.
唯一符合你要求的场地
The only range
that matches your requirements.
你应该睡一会
You should sleep.
明天要开长途
You have a long drive tomorrow,
我要查一下奥赖恩
and l need to go to city hall
and pull up Oline's legal history.
先别那样做
l wouldn't do that. Not till l get back.
等我回来再说 如果我是对的
有人杀了四个平民
lf l'm right,
someone killed four random people
目的不是让调查员去查奥赖恩
so no one would look directly at Oline.
如果我分析得对
只要提他的名字 你就会送命
And if l'm right, just saying her name
could get you killed.
- 你认为我会害怕吗
- 你很聪明 那不是明摆着的吗
-You saying l should be scared?
-Well, are you smart?
显然
Obviously.
那就不用害怕
Then don't be scared.
到底要我找什么
What exactly am l looking for?
杀死这个女孩的人
Someone who could kill that girl
with one punch.
你要的人在1109室
Oh, you want the guy in 1109.
厄尼-约翰逊
Ernie Johnson.
你要看看吗
You'll see.
快下车
Out of the car!
他是我们要抓的嫌疑犯 快跑
That's our suspect! Move, move!
疑犯在65号公路向北行驶
Suspect is headed north
on State Route 65.
我需要增援和空中支援
l need backup and air support.
等一下
Hold up!
没有人
All clear!
哦 天呐
我就是不敢相信 不敢相信
Oh, God,
l just don't believe it. l don't believe it!
我刚签发了逮捕令
l issued the warrant an hour ago.
有人看到雷彻
According to the victim's boss,
今天去了她的商店
Reacher was seen at her
place of work this morning.
他还威胁她老板
Where he threatened her boss.
他开的是杰布-奥利沃朋友的车
The car he was driving tonight
belonged to a friend of Jeb Oliver's.
他打了那个人
The man he assaulted.
不 是他们打了雷彻
No, those guys assaulted Reacher.
在杰布家
Reacher put three more men
in the hospital
雷彻把三个人打伤住院
this afternoon at Jeb Oliver's place.
是开杰布的车去的那里
After arriving in Jeb Oliver's car.
杰布出院后 再也没人看见他
And Jeb hasn't been seen
since he left the hospital.
如果你知道雷彻在哪  告诉我们
Helen, if you know where Reacher is,
you need to tell us.
我不知道 几个小时前
我离开办公室后
l don't know where he is.
l have not seen him
就再也没见到他
since he left my office a few hours ago.
- 我认为她说是的实话
- 你认为 爸 该死
-l think she's telling the truth.
-You think, Dad? Fuck you!
我告诉过你不要接近他
Hey, l told you not to go near him.
你进入我的家就像审犯人一样审我
You come into my home
and you treat me like l'm an accessory!
-Please! You know...
-All right. All right. Come on. Enough.
- 好了 我来处理
- 我没说完
-Look, let me handle it.
-l'm not done.
你俩说完了 出去
You're both done. Just get out.
这是海伦
This is Helen.
我猜警察在那里
-l'm guessing the police are there?
-Yep.
是的
我猜不出30秒
By your response l'm guessing
l have about 30 seconds
他们就会要你手里的电话
before you hand them the phone.
会的
lf that.
如果他们能陷害巴尔
lf you believe someone
could frame Barr,
也能陷害我
you have to believe
they could do the same to me.
我想有这个可能
l suppose that's possible.
她是一个可爱的孩子 海伦
She was a sweet kid, Helen.
他们是因为我 才杀死了她
And they killed her because of me.
他们逼我不插手此事
They want me to run.
我决不
But l won't.
-我一定要查清
-这不是个好主意
-l'm going to finish this.
-No, that's not a good idea.
听好
Listen.
第二
Two things. One, l...
我偷了你的汽车
l stole your car.
如果你要结束合作
lf you want to end this,
挂上电话报案 车丢了
just hang up the phone
and report it missing.
我能理解
And l'll understand.
还有事吗
And anything else?
早点告诉你怕你接受不了
l thought l'd be pushing it
if l mentioned this earlier.
我担心发生意外
Now l guess all bets are off.
对爱默生和你父亲谈话要小心
You need to watch what you say
to Emerson and your father.
我认为他们的其中之一参与了此案
l think one of them is in on it.
好  谢谢通知 我挂了
All right. Thanks for calling. l have to go.
等等 从第一天开始 我就被跟踪了
Wait. l've been followed from day one.
只有三个人知道我在这里
Only three people knew l was here.
爱默生，你的父亲和你
Emerson, your father and you.
你自己想下
You need to ask yourself,
帮巴尔洗清罪名 谁损失最大
who has the most to lose
if we clear Barr?
谁警告你要离开我
Who tried to warn you off me?
当然 我可能是错误的
如果你认为我是
Of course, l could be wrong.
lf you think l am,
就挂上电话
just hand over the phone.
进一步调查就没有意义了
There's no sense getting any deeper.
你在和谁说话
Who's that you're talking to?
办公室的人
The office.
我们谈完了吗
Are we done?
海伦 听着
Helen, listen.
-我们需要
-晚安
-We need to...
-Good night.
你这里有优秀的射手吗
You got some fine shooters here.
想找优秀的
Fine as frog's hair.
很难
Rarer, too.
大多数来这儿的人 根本就不会射击
'Cause most of them fellas out there
can't shoot worth a damn.
让他们把3发子弹打中靶子
You ask them to put
three rounds in the black, well,
根本打不中
they'll suck it.
- 我要找店主
- 我就是 马丁-凯时
-l'm looking for the owner.
-That'd be me. Martin Cash.
艾伦-沃德
Aaron Ward.
我能为你做什么 先生
What can l do you for,Mr Ward? Ward?
我正在找一位我的朋友
一起在伊拉克服过役
Yeah. l'm looking for a friend of mine.
We served in lraq.
他消失了 知道吗
The guy just dropped
off the grid, you know?
常有这种事
-lt happens. Yep.
-Yeah. Yeah.
他曾是名狙击手
Anyway, he was a shooter.
最后一次听到他的消息时 他还活着
Last l heard, he lived
around here somewhere and l...
他什么时候退役的
When did he get out of the Army?
我没说他是军人
Well, l didn't say the Army.
你说过的 你是不是锅盖头
Well, you said you served with him.
You're no jarhead.
明眼人一眼就能看出来
Man on a flying horse could see that.
好吧 我的父亲是海军陆战队的
Well, my father was in the Corps,
if that helps.
这只能说明你是半个强人
Well, that makes you half human.
你朋友的名字
Your friend got a name?
詹姆斯-巴尔
Yeah. James Barr.
James Barr.
没听过
Never heard of him.
我认为你有
l think you have.
我认为你些恐惧
l think you've been dreading the moment
警察来过
some cop comes in here
asking after him.
这让你很恐慌
Because it's for sure
some soccer mom around here
这附近足球妈妈更担心你的射击场
is more worried about your range than
she is about the pool in her backyard
而不是自家后院的游泳池
or the drain cleaner under her sink.
巴尔在100英里以外杀人也没什么
Wouldn't matter to her
if Barr did his killing 100 miles away,
可他是在你这儿训练的
only that he came here to rehearse.
足球妈妈一纸诉状就能让你停业
She'd have a case to shut you down
你会无计可施
and nothing better to do.
你想怎样
What do you want?
我想要知道巴尔的朋友是谁
l want to know who Barr's friends were.
这帮家伙
Those boys out there,
当你触动他们的权利里 他们很敏感
they're mighty touchy when it comes
to their constitutional rights.
告诉他们 警察问过我的会员会怎样
Suppose l tell them a cop is in here
asking after my members?
- 我不是警官
- 你是作什么的?
-l'm not a cop.
-What are you?
我是巴尔的律师
l work for Barr's attorney.
我们有理由相信他是无辜的
We have reason to believe
he's innocent.
胡说 就算他是有罪
The hell you say.
我是唯一跑来调查他的人
Be that as it may, l'm the only one
who's bothered to track him this far.
你帮我一次 我帮你解决债务问题
You help me out, l'll be in your debt.
而且如果不帮呢
And if l don't?
也许你能教足球
Maybe you can coach soccer.
你把3发子弹打中靶心时我们再谈
You put three in the centre
and maybe we'll talk.
能给几发热身吗
Can l have a few to warm up?
偏右6英
Six inches right.
这是你的第二枪 沃德先生
That's your mulligan, Mr Ward.
Play ball!
准备 开始
Let's go.
你的手有点生了 雷彻先生
You're a little rusty, Mr Reacher.
十年前 有人用这个名子参加射击大赛
l saw a man by that name
shoot for the Wimbledon Cup,
什么 十年前
what, ten years ago.
我肯定你没打过扬基队的二垒手
And l'm pretty sure you never
played second base for the Yankees
在 1925 年
in 1925.
现在
Now,
我将回答你的问题
l'll answer one question.
谁是最好的射手
Who's your best shooter?
詹姆斯-巴尔
James Barr.
听到他打死人 就把这些摘下来了
l pulled all these down
as soon as l heard about the shooting.
那是人生平见过的
That's the best shot
最棒的枪法
l ever seen this side of civilian life.
我告诉你 巴尔在部队也没打过这么好
Suppose l told you Barr wasn't this
good on his best day in the Army.
这是我亲手贴上的靶子
上面有我的笔迹
l handed out those targets myself.
That's my scrawl on every one.
你也把靶子放在最远处吗
Do you hang them downrange, too?
你是什么意思
What, are you serious?
我是说巴尔可能有个朋友
l'm saying
it's possible that Barr had a friend.
他换掉了射击场里的靶子
One who switched the targets
on the range.
也许是巴尔让他换的
Maybe Barr let him.
当他的大名挂在墙上 感觉自己是冠军
Made him feel like King Shit
having his name up on your wall.
我从没见过一个真正的射手
会为了自己的妈妈这么做
l never saw one real shooter
who would do that for his own mother.
除非他想陷害她妈妈
杀了好几个人
Unless he was framing his mother
for multiple murder
而且是在你这个射击场干的
and using your range to do it.
巴尔不是一个人来的 对吗
Barr didn't come alone, did he?
如果他们发现录像 就会有人来杀你
You know, one of these nuts is likely
to kill you, they find that camera, there.
录像就在这
Hell, the camera's there
没有疯子会杀我
'cause one of these nuts
is likely to kill me.
那是巴尔
There's Barr.
我一直很喜欢他
l always liked him. Always liked him.
在那里
There.
他
Him.
混蛋
That son of a bitch.
海伦-罗丁
Helen Rodin speaking.
找到凶手备选人照片
Got a candidate for our shooter.
可能是他的指纹
Picture, possible prints
还有个证人
and one pissed-off eyewitness.
我现在不能说话
l can't talk right now.
我3小时后回去
Just give me three hours to get back.
这之前不要和任何人谈话
And don't talk to anyone until l get there.
我会处理这事 谢谢
l'll look into that, thanks.
这些是我今天早上拿到的资料
This is just
what l could pull this morning.
纳税记录 市里和州里的项目批准书
Tax records, city and state
permit applications, contract bids.
是格鲁吉亚一家空壳公司
Shell corporation in Georgia.
挨着俄罗斯的国家 不在佛罗里达
That's the one next to Russia,
not Florida.
他们开发一个城市
They work one city at a time,
acquiring a local construction concern
要求当地建筑公司在开工前
just ahead of major civic redevelopment.
先建造没人需要的桥梁
没人用的高速公路
They build bridges no one needs.
Highways no one uses.
他们像癌细胞一样不停地生长
They're like a cancer.
A cell that won't stop growing.
在15年里搬了12次家
They moved 12 times in 15 years.
Atlanta, Albuquerque,
亚特兰大 阿尔布开克 奥斯汀
俄克拉荷马
Austin, Oklahoma city, Sacramento.
被指记账的名单中总是有它
Always amidst allegations of corruption
包括几千万公共资金不翼而飞
including millions of dollars
in missing public funds.
可却从来未被调查过 甚至从没被质询过
And yet never an investigation.
Never even an inquiry.
这个公司口碑极佳
lt's as if Lebendauer Enterprises
were above reproach.
也许那些是竞争对手的指责
Well, maybe that's because
出高价
the allegations come
from the competition.
充满敌意
Outbid. Bitter.
比如奥赖恩-阿彻
Like Oline Archer.
也许乐班德尔公司在跟重要部门合作
Or maybe Lebendauer
has the cooperation of key officials.
合作不畅时 他们就杀掉那些收买不了的
And maybe
when that cooperation isn't enough,
比如奥赖恩
they kill people who won't be bought off.
Like Oline Archer.
这样的传言你相信多少
Helen, how much of this
do you honestly believe?
我相信多少没关系
lt doesn't matter how much l believe.
甚至连我能证实多少都无关紧要
lt doesn't even matter
how much l can prove.
重要的是其中有多少是真的
lt only matters how much is true.
你知道吗 你这是幻听幻觉
Do you know how delusional you sound?
你怎么了
What happened to you?
你真想他死吗
Are you really so set on putting
this man to death that you'd ignore...
所有的文件都是我自己获得的
l pulled all of this paper
under my own name.
如果杰克雷-彻说得对
lf Jack Reacher's right,
我的命 你女儿的生命
my life, your daughter's life,
现在有危险了
is in danger now.
我接下来出什么事都是你造成的
Whatever happens to me next
is on your head,
无论是不是与你有关
whether you're involved or not.
你是地方检察官
我已经给了你确凿的证据
You are the District Attorney
and l've given you compelling evidence
调查尔班德尔企业
to investigate Lebendauer Enterprises.
你的下个动作
将告诉我你的立场
Your next move
will tell me which side you're on.
哦
我知道了 这是一个测试
l see. lt's a test.
好吧 我很难相信你 但是我爱你
Well, this may be hard for you
to believe, but l do love you.
我不会视而不见的
And obviously l'm not
going to turn a blind eye,
无论我发现这些事有多么荒诞
no matter how absurd l find all of this.
如果你真的相信你有危险
So, if you really believe
that you're in danger,
如果你相信
if you believe that,
那么接下来的任务
then the next order of business,
就是马上对你进行保护监禁
is to put you
in protective custody right now.
如果你也是同谋呢
And how safe will l be
if you're part of it?
天呐 海伦
Jesus, Helen.
哦 嗨
Hey.
公事还是私事
Business meeting or personal?
很难分辨
Hard to tell them apart.
我打赌
l'll bet.
-海伦
-不是
Helen?
No.
对不起 打错了
Sorry, wrong number.
你是雷彻吗
ls this Reacher?
你是谁
Who is this?
我是雷彻
ls this Reacher?
是你 车里的人
lt's you. The guy from the car.
是你的男朋友
lt's your boyfriend.
雷彻 是你吗
Reacher, is it you?
海伦 你受伤了吗
Helen, are you hurt?
如果你一小时后不来 就废了她
Well, she's gonna be
if you're not here in one hour.
你追得我到处跑
Do l have to tell you how this works?
怕我被虽人跟踪
You'll bounce me around
to make sure l'm not followed,
让我走进埋伏 杀掉我
then walk me into
an ambush and kill me.
你毁了我的惊喜
Aw, you ruined my surprise.
好 我会给你个更好的
Well, l can do one better.
我去过关键小溪射击场
拿到了照片和指纹
l went down to the gun range
at Hinge Creek.
我要去联帮调查局
l got the picture, prints,
and l'm going to the Feds.
如果你敢动那个律师
The lawyer's all yours.
叫翟科来
Get the Zec.
我想杀了你
On second thought, l'd like to kill you.
胜者为王
Let's say winner take all.
听着 你这个混蛋
Listen to me, you prick.
你要是不过来 我就杀了这个婊子
l will kill this bitch
if you're not here in one...
该死
Shit!
你认为我是个英雄的
You think l'm a hero?
我不是英雄 我只是个游侠
l am not a hero.
l'm a drifter with nothing to lose.
你杀了那个女孩来陷害我
You killed that girl to put me in a frame.
我要扒了你的皮 喝干你的血
l mean to beat you to death
and drink your blood from a boot.
听着 这么办吧 你给我地址
Now, this is how it's going to work.
You're gonna give me the address
等我准备好了 就去找你算账
and l'll be along
when l am damn good and ready.
如果我打电话她不接
lf she doesn't answer the phone
when l call this number,
我会认为你杀了她
if l even think you've hurt her,
我就消失
l disappear.
如果你聪明点 我不是威胁你
你在明我在暗
And if you're smart, that scares you,
because l'm in your blind spot
而且我又没有别的事要做
and l have nothing better to do.
你有笔吗
You got a pen?
不需要
Don't need one.
如果每次军方来找陆战队员帮忙
我都收一美元好了
lf l had a dollar for every time
the Army called the Corps for help.
- 你有东西给我
- 是的
-You have something for me?
-Yeah.
在这
Here.
你在开玩笑, 对不对
You're kidding, right?
虽然我十年前看过你射击
Just because l saw you
shoot ten years ago
可并不意味着我会让你用我的枪
doesn't mean l'll let you
kill some asshole with my gun.
我告诉过你情况非常危急
l told you how serious this was.
我也被卷进去了 对吗
And l showed up, didn't l?
咱们大干一场吧
So let's get to it.
杀你的凶手会到这来
Now, your shooter will be
在那些灯光后面
right up there
behind those lights. Okay?
他能朝这条路射击
He can cover both roads
coming and going.
你一站起来就能击毙你
And kill you
just as soon as you stand up.
好吧 你能干掉了吗
Well, can you take him out?
什么 干掉他
What, to dinner you mean?
听着 雷彻
我不知道你都和什么人交往
Look, l don't know the type of people
you normally associate with, Reacher.
我没那个习惯 毫无准备就走进荒野
But l'm not in the habit of driving out
to the boonies at the drop of a hat
解决掉几个陌生人 好吗
and just picking off
some total strangers, all right?
那些灯太亮 我什么也看不清
Anyway, l can't see anything,
not with them lights up.
那就打灭它
So shoot them out.
可以
然后他就知道我在哪了
Yeah, sure.
And then he knows right where l am.
我这不是引火烧身吗
l might as well set myself on fire.
不 先生 他开枪 我才开枪
No, sir. l'll start shooting when he does.
你说我们引他先开枪怎么样
And how do you propose
we get him started?
好吧  你可以开始跑了
Well, you could always start running.
你的眼睛怎么了
What's wrong with your eye?
闭目养神
l'm saving my night vision.
老牛仔 问你个私人问题
Hey, Gunny, you mind if l ask you
kind of a personal question?
你认为我不会再射击吗
What, you don't think
l can shoot any more?
好枪法很难保持一辈子
lt is a perishable skill.
是啊
Yeah, well,
太阳一小时后就升起来了
the sun will be up in an hour.
我们走
Let's get going.
我听到他们叫你翟科
l heard them call you the Zec.
那是囚犯的意思 是吗
That means "prisoner."
是的
Yes?
告诉我 杀了这么多人
Tell me, killing all those people,
我相信你赚的钱
l have to believe the money
you're making
不可能足够用来
can't possibly be enough to just...
说够了吗
Enough?
根本没有这回事
There is no such thing.
我们只拿属于我们的东西
We take what can be taken.
我们就是这么做的
This is what we do.
而你呢
And you?
他我能理解 可是你呢
This one l think l understand, but you?
你是为什么
Why'd you do it?
我没得选择
You make it sound like l had a choice.
你没有吗
Oh, didn't you?
你会懂的
You'll see.
你们应该知道 我们已经采取了措施
You should know l've taken steps,
that if anything happens...
如果你发生意外
也会在你父亲面前
lf anything happens to you,
it will happen in front of your father
他祈求留你一条小命
while he begs for your life.
现在你必须说服他忘掉这一切
You should never have involved him.
为了你
Now you will have to convince him
to forget,for your sake
也为了他
and for his.
你不说话 我能看到你眼中充满了蔑视
You say nothing,
but l see defiance in your eyes.
这种眼神我见多了
That is a look l have seen
many, many times.
等那个大兵来了之后
When the soldier comes,
你亲眼看着他死去
那会改变你的想法
when you watch how he dies,
it will change you.
到时你就会想忘记我了
You will want to forget me then.
雷彻
Reacher?
你好吗
Are you okay?
他们要杀你
They're ready for you.
他们这么认为
They'd like to think so.
别来 不要为了我
Don't do this.
Please don't do this. Not for me.
海伦, 他们不会伤害你的
Listen, Helen, they're not gonna
在没有抓到我之前
hurt you until they have me.
And that's never going to happen.
你听我说
You hear me?
你要坚持住
You just hang in there.
我会去救你
'Cause l'm coming to get you.
快说你相信我
Now say you believe me.
我相信你
l believe you.
这是个馊主意
This was a bad idea.
老年仔 准备射击
Any time now, Gunny.
该死
Shit.
你在哪里 老牛仔
Where the hell are you, Gunny?
臭手
Suck it!
你该走了
You should go.
Toss it.
我知道你是在那里 爱默生
l know you're in there, Emerson.
我有你的犯罪证据
lt was staring me right in the face.
一个证据不能解释一切
The one piece that just didn't fit.
硬币
The quarter.
没人想到计时表的硬币就是证据
Nobody would have thought
to dump that meter.
连我都不会这么想
Not even me.
你错怪了我的父亲
You were wrong about my father.
我不会扩大事态
l wouldn't make a big thing of it.
他是谁
Who is he?
他是二号人物
That's John Doe Number Two.
暗杀行动的策划者
The man on the grassy knoll.
The thing under the bed.
他们叫他翟科
They call him the Zec.
翟科 就是囚犯
Zec? Prisoner.
你的真正名字是什么
What's your real name?
我是十月出生的
l was born in October.
当我数到我生日的那月 我就开枪
When l get to my birthday,
l'm gonna pull the trigger.
一  二
One. Two.
切诺维克
Chelovek. Zec Chelovek.
切诺维克 翟科-切诺维克
Chelovek?
切诺维克是人名
Chelovek? Human.
你叫囚犯人
Prisoner Human Being.
- 那是你的真名吗
- 我就记得这些
-That's your real name?
-That is all l remember.
打电话给警察
Call the police.
你刚才真想杀了他吗
Were you really going to shoot him?
不会的
l knew l wouldn't have to.
看一眼就知道会是想活的人
One look at this guy and you know
he'll do anything to survive.
你看一眼就知道我不是吹牛的人
One look at me
and you know l'm not bluffing.
我有件急事
Yes, l have an emergency at...
好 我等着
Yes, l'll hold.
我们不着急
We're in no hurry.
你住监狱 就像在家里一样舒服
With a name like yours,
you're gonna feel right at home.
监狱 在美国
Prison? ln America?
能去美国监狱 就像住进养老院
A retirement home.
lf l go to prison at all.
你认为能逃脱罪名吗
You think you're gonna walk?
你是个无家可归的人 被通缉的杀人犯
You are a homeless drifter
wanted for murder.
我是在错误时间来这里的老头
Meanwhile, l am an old man
in the wrong place at the wrong time.
多亏了你
Thanks to you,
who is left to say othewise? Who?
谁呢
对 我有一件急事
Yes, hello? Yes, there's...
l have an emergency.
我们走着瞧 看谁进监狱
We'll see which one of us
goes to prison.
也许有三四个人死
There are maybe
three, four people dead.
- 好
- 我的打赌
-Okay.
-My bet?
没人
Neither one.
你做了什么
What did you do?
这现场看上去像什么
What's it look like?
那真相怎么办
What about the truth?
怎么才能抓到真到的凶手
What about getting the guys
who really did this?
将他们绳之以法
What about bringing him to justice?
我刚刚做完了
l just did.
怎样洗清巴尔的罪名
What about clearing Barr?
What about clearing you?
洗清你的罪名
l have faith you'll sort it out.
你会解决的 我听说你当上了检察官
And l hear you have an in
with the local D.A.
这期间你会干什么去
But what happens to you
in the meantime?
和以前一样 继续流浪
l keep moving. Same as always.
等等 那是我的汽车吗
Wait, is that my car?
这位女士
This the lady?
海伦-罗丁,马丁-凯时
Helen Rodin, Martin Cash.
幸会
A pleasure.
你看起来糟透了 大兵
You look like hell there, Army.
你问我是不是害怕象巴尔那样的结果
You asked if l was afraid
l'd end up like Barr. l'm not.
我不怕 我恐怕最终会像这家伙一样
l'm afraid l'll end up like this guy.
这里有好几具尸体 咱们走吧
There's a lot of dead bodies out here.
So let's get to it.
- 我们该去哪儿呢
- 等等 这就完了
-We should probably go.
-Wait. That's it?
结束了吗
lt's just over?
你会没事的 大律师
You'll be all right, counsellor.
不 我需要你的时候怎么办
No. What if l need you?
How will l find you?
你不需要我了
You don't need me.
不需要了
Not any more.
记下她的电话号友 我们走
Get her number. Let's go!
我是海伦-罗丁 你的律师
l'm Helen Rodin, your attorney.
本次谈话受律师诉讼委托人权益保护
This conversation is protected
by attorney-client privilege.
你明白这什么意思吗
You understand what that means?
是的
Yeah.
警察没找你谈过话 对吗
Now, the police didn't
talk to you, did they?
没有我在场 他们不能和你谈话
They're not allowed
to do that without me here.
情况多严重
How bad was it?
有多少人
How many did l...
你不记得那件事了
You don't remember
anything about the incident?
不记得
No.
我听到护士和警察在外面的谈话
But l could hear the nurses
talking to those cops out there.
我不记得自己为什么要杀人
l don't even remember wanting to do it!
这一点我不抗辩
Look, l'm not gonna fight this.
如果他们说是我干的 那我就干了
lf they say l done it, then l did.
以前我也干过这事
l done things before.
我做了坏事
l did something bad.
很坏
Real bad.
很久以前
A long time ago.
我逃脱了罪名
And l got away with it.
詹姆斯
James,
这地方你熟吗
how well do you know this place?
很熟悉
Pretty well.
要是你做 你会怎么做
And how do you think
you would have done it?
我猜
l guess
我会把车停在调整公路上
l would have parked up on the highway.
让太阳照在我背上
The sun would be at my back
that time of day.
我有面包车
l got a van.
枪架在车后部
Set up in back.
用不着担心弹壳会飞出去
Wouldn't have to worry about my brass.
不留痕迹你 说我这么做对吗
Get away real clean, too.
That sound about right?
听上去你是行家
Sounds as if you know your stuff.
我忘记你的名字
l forget your name.
海伦
lt's Helen.
海伦-罗丁
Helen Rodin.
你会没事的 詹姆斯
You're going to be okay, James.
我会保护你
l am gonna take care of you.
你不能保护我
You can't protect me.
没有人能 有人要害我
No one can.
什么
From what?
谁
From who?
有个人
There's this guy.
他好像是警官
He's a kind of cop.
至少他过去是
At least he used to be.
他不在乎法律
He doesn't care about the law.
不在乎证据
He doesn't care about proof.
只在乎什么是公正
He only cares about what's right.
Look at me when l'm talking to you!
他知道我做什么
He knows what l did.
他知道我在哪里
He knows where l am.
他向我承诺过
And this guy, he made me a promise.
如果我再遇到麻烦
l said, shut your mouth!
lf l ever got in trouble again,
他会来救我
he'd be there.